<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Bryce's Journal Of Thoughts]]></title>
  <link href="http://brycep.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brycep.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-07T16:28:01-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://brycep.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Bryce]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Starting a New Blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://brycep.github.io/blog/2014/11/22/new-blog/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-22T10:05:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://brycep.github.io/blog/2014/11/22/new-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s been a while since I&rsquo;ve had the ability to do much exploration into new technologies outside of work. But occasionally I do enjoy tinkering around with ideas and putting them out there, so I decided an easy way of doing this might be to start a new blog.</p>

<p>There are a lot of great, free blogs out there, but I chose <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> because of its simplicity.  Octopress generates static HTML pages using a handful of Ruby scripts.  There&rsquo;s no database, no server setup, just plane old HTML.  It can be deployed anywhere, and it should still provide a good platform for JavaScript or code examples.</p>

<p>Github Pages provide free hosting for static pages.  Deploying a change to the site is as easy as pushing my changes to Github.  To top it off, I can blog inside a terminal window using my favorite text editor (vim).</p>

<p>All you need to get going is a free Github account.  Just create a repository named [username].github.io, and follow <a href="https://pages.github.com">these</a> instructions.</p>

<p>Since Octopress is another project on Github, I forked the code to my own account so that I can clone it to whatever computer I wanted, then cloned it to my laptop.  Configuration is pretty easy and well documented in the <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/configuring/">Octopress Documentation</a>.  For now all my blog source will be up on Github here: <a href="https://github.com/brycep/octopress/tree/myblog">https://github.com/brycep/octopress/tree/myblog</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
