<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ui | Bryce's Journal Of Thoughts]]></title>
  <link href="http://brycep.github.io/blog/categories/ui/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brycep.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-08T21:02:25-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://brycep.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Bryce]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using CSS Animations]]></title>
    <link href="http://brycep.github.io/blog/2014/12/08/using-css-animations/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-08T21:35:54-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://brycep.github.io/blog/2014/12/08/using-css-animations</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the reasons I started this blog is to have a platform to experiment with UI design.
Octopress is amazingly flexible.  You can change almost every aspect of it, and even if there&rsquo;s something the
author hadn&rsquo;t thought of, you have all the source, so you can implement whatever you want.</p>

<p>After playing around with the side, I decided I wanted to try to use CSS to animate the sidebar expanding and
collapsing.  CSS transitions are part of the CSS3 set of specifications.  They&rsquo;re a remarkably simple yet powerful
way to put simple animations into your static HTML pages.</p>

<p>When I dug into the Octopress HTML, I found the sidebar expands and contracts when the JavaScript code toggles a
CSS class called &ldquo;collapse-sidebar&rdquo;.  The &ldquo;collapse-sidebar&rdquo; class moves the right margin of the sidebar back and forth
from a negative value to 0.  By specifying a CSS transition on the right margin, you can make the browser animate
when it applies the new class.</p>

<p>The CSS transition property has 4 parts to it:</p>

<pre><code>transition: &lt;property&gt; &lt;duration&gt; &lt;transition style&gt; &lt;delay&gt;;
</code></pre>

<p>In my case, I want &ldquo;margin-right&rdquo; to animate for .7 of a second.</p>

<p>Adding the following code to the #content class makes any change to the margin-right property become animated</p>

<pre><code>#content {
  transition: margin-right 0.7s;
}
</code></pre>

<p>Give it a try.  Click on the arrows at the top of the sidebar on this page and watch the sidebar slide in and out.</p>

<p>Find more information about CSS3 transitions at the link below.  They&rsquo;re a lot of fun to play around with!</p>

<p>(<a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Guide/CSS/Using_CSS_transitions">https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Guide/CSS/Using_CSS_transitions</a>)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
